<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="monuments">Monuments</string>
    <string name="mosque">Mosques</string>
    <string name="beach">Beach</string>
    <string name="university">University</string>
    <string name="egypt">Egypt</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="visite">Visite</string>
    <string name="read_more">Read More</string>

    <string name="egypt_overview">
        officially the Arab Republic of Egypt, is a transcontinental
        country spanning the northeast corner of Africa and southwest corner
        of Asia by a land bridge formed by the Sinai Peninsula. Egypt is a Mediterranean country
        bordered by the Gaza Strip and Israel to the northeast, the Gulf of Aqaba to the east,
        the Red Sea to the east and south, Sudan to the south, and Libya to the west. Across the
        Gulf of Aqaba lies Jordan, and across from the Sinai Peninsula lies Saudi Arabia,
        although Jordan and Saudi Arabia do not share a land border with Egypt.
    </string>
    <string name="egypt_site">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egypt</string>
    <string name="egypt_latitude">26.8348894</string>
    <string name="egypt_Longitude">26.3802996</string>


    <string name="tutankhamun">Tutankhamun</string>
    <string name="tut_description">
        was an Egyptian pharaoh of the 18th dynasty
        (ruled c. 1332–1323 BC in the conventional chronology),
        during the period of Egyptian history known as the New Kingdom or sometimes
        the New Empire Period. He has, since the discovery of his intact tomb, been referred to
        colloquially as King Tut. His original name, Tutankhaten, means "Living Image of Aten",
        while Tutankhamun means "Living Image of Amun". In hieroglyphs, the name Tutankhamun was
        typically written Amen-tut-ankh, because of a scribal custom that placed a divine name at the
        beginning of a phrase to show appropriate reverence.He is possibly also the Nibhurrereya of the
        Amarna letters, and likely the 18th dynasty king Rathotis who, according to Manetho, an ancient historian,
        had reigned for nine years—a figure that conforms with Flavius Josephus's version of Manetho's Epitome.
    </string>
    <string name="tut_latitude">30.0477508</string>
    <string name="tut_Longitude">31.2340181</string>


    <string name="karnak">Karnak</string>
    <string name="karnak_description">
        The Karnak Temple Complex, commonly known as Karnak
        comprises a vast mix of decayed temples, chapels, pylons,
        and other buildings in Egypt. Construction at the complex began
        during the reign of Senusret I in the Middle Kingdom and continued into the
        Ptolemaic period, although most of the extant buildings date from the New Kingdom.
        The area around Karnak was the ancient Egyptian Ipet-isut ("The Most Selected of Places")
        and the main place of worship of the eighteenth dynasty Theban Triad with the god Amun as
        its head. It is part of the monumental city of Thebes. The Karnak complex gives its name to the nearby,
        and partly surrounded, modern village of El-Karnak, 2.5 kilometres (1.6 miles) north of Luxor.
    </string>
    <string name="karnak_latitude">30.0538143</string>
    <string name="karnak_Longitude">31.2584193</string>


    <string name="citadel_of_qaitbay">The Citadel of Qaitbay</string>
    <string name="citadel_of_qaitbay_description">
        The Citadel of Qaitbay (or the Fort of Qaitbay) is a 15th-century defensive
        fortress located on the Mediterranean sea coast, in Alexandria, Egypt. It was
        established in 1477 AD (882 AH) by Sultan Al-Ashraf Sayf al-Din Qa\'it Bay.
        The Citadel is situated on the eastern side of the northern tip of Pharos Island at the mouth of the
        Eastern Harbour.The Qaitbay Citadel in Alexandria is considered one of the most important defensive strongholds,
        not only in Egypt, but also along the Mediterranean Sea coast. It formulated an important part of the fortification
        system of Alexandria in the 15th century AD.
    </string>
    <string name="citadel_of_qaitbay_latitude">31.214011</string>
    <string name="citadel_of_qaitbay_Longitude">29.8834496</string>


    <string name="abu_smbel">Abu Simbel</string>
    <string name="abu_smbel_description">
        The Abu Simbel temples are two massive rock temples at Abu Simbel, a village in Nubia,
        southern Egypt, near the border with Sudan. They are situated on the western bank of Lake Nasser,
        about 230 km southwest of Aswan (about 300 km by road). The complex is part of the UNESCO World Heritage
        Site known as the "Nubian Monuments", which run from Abu Simbel downriver to Philae (near Aswan). The twin
        temples were originally carved out of the mountainside in the 13th century BC, during the 19th dynasty reign of
        the Pharaoh Ramesses II. They serve as a lasting monument to the king and his queen Nefertari, and commemorate his
        victory at the Battle of Kadesh. Their huge external rock relief figures have become iconic.
    </string>
    <string name="abu_smbel_latitude">22.3372319</string>
    <string name="abu_smbel_Longitude">31.6236103</string>


    <string name="al_rifai_mosque">Al-Rifa\'i Mosque</string>
    <string name="al_rifai_mosque_description">
        Al-Rifa\'i Mosque, is located in Cairo, Egypt, in Midan al-Qal\'a,
        adjacent to the Cairo Citadel. The building is located opposite the Mosque-Madrassa
        of Sultan Hassan, which dates from around 1361, and was architecturally conceived as a complement
        to the older structure. This was part of a vast campaign by the 19th century rulers of Egypt to both
        associate themselves with the perceived glory of earlier periods in Egypt's Islamic history and modernize
        the city. The mosque was constructed next to two large public squares and off of several European style boulevards
        constructed around the same time.
    </string>
    <string name="al_rifai_mosque_latitude">30.0327091</string>
    <string name="al_rifai_mosque_Longitude">31.2548142</string>


    <string name="al_hussein_mosque">Al-Hussain Mosque</string>
    <string name="al_hussein_mosque_description">
        The Al-Hussain Mosque is a mosque built in 1154. (Alternative transliterations include Husayn,
        Hussain, Husayn, and Hussayn; also, the mosque\'s name is prefixed by the honorific title Sayyidna).
        The mosque is located in Cairo, Egypt, near the Khan El-Khalili bazaar. It is considered to be one of the
        holiest Islamic sites in Egypt.The mosque was built on the cemetery of the Fatimid caliphs, though this was not
        known until the site\'s archaeological excavation. It is named for Muhammad\'s grandson, Hussain ibn Ali. Dawoodi Bohra
        and other Shia Muslims believe that Husayn\'s head is buried on the grounds of the mosque. The complex includes a mausoleum,
        which dates back to the mosque\'s original construction in 1154.
    </string>
    <string name="al_hussein_mosque_latitude">30.048237</string>
    <string name="al_hussein_mosque_Longitude">31.2614963</string>


    <string name="mosque_of_al_hakim">Mosque of al-Hakim</string>
    <string name="mosque_of_al_hakim_description">
        The Mosque of al-Hakim, nicknamed al-Anwar, is a major Islamic religious site in Cairo, Egypt.
        It is named after Al-Hakim bi-Amr Allah (985–1021), the sixth Fatimid caliph and 16th Ismaili Imam.
        The mosque was originally built as an enclosure by the Fatimid vizier Gawhar Al-Siqilli (c. 928–992),
        but was incorporated into the extended fortifications built by Badr al-Jamali. It consists of an irregular
        rectangle with four arcades surrounding the courtyard. An unusual feature is the monumental entrance with its
        projecting stone porch. It is located in "Islamic Cairo", on the east side of Muizz Street, just south of Bab Al-Futuh
        (the northern gate).
    </string>
    <string name="mosque_of_al_hakim_latitude">30.0518815</string>
    <string name="mosque_of_al_hakim_Longitude">30.0518815</string>


    <string name="cairo">Cairo University</string>
    <string name="cairo_description">
        Cairo University is Egypt\'s premier public university. Its main campus is in Giza,
        immediately across the Nile from Cairo. It was founded on 21 December 1908; however,
        after being housed in various parts of Cairo, its faculties, beginning with the Faculty of Arts,
        were established on its current main campus in Giza in October 1929. It is the second oldest institution
        of higher education in Egypt after Al Azhar University, notwithstanding the pre-existing higher professional
        schools that later became constituent colleges of the university. It was founded and funded as the Egyptian University
        by a committee of private citizens with royal patronage in 1908 and became a state institution under King Fuad I in 1925.
        In 1940, four years following his death, the University was renamed King Fuad I University in his honor. It was renamed a
        second time after the Free Officer’s Coup of 1952.The University currently enrolls approximately 155,000 students in 22 faculties.
        It counts three Nobel Laureates among its graduates and is one of the 50 largest institutions of higher education in the world by
        enrollment
    </string>
    <string name="cairo_latitude">30.0273365</string>
    <string name="cairo_Longitude">31.2063854</string>


    <string name="benha">Banha University</string>
    <string name="benha_description">
        Banha University is an Egyptian university in the Egyptian city of Banha, the capital of Al Qalyubiyah governorate.
        It was established according to a decree on 25 November 1976 as a branch from Zagazig University in Banha, with the faculties
        of Commerce, Education, Agriculture of Moshtohor, Engineering of Shobra and Medicine.
        In 1981–1982, the faculties of Arts, Science of Banha and Veterinary Medicine of Moshtohor were founded.
        On 1 August 2005 it became an independent university from Zagazig University. The previous president of the university
        is Professor Hosam-ed-din Mohammad Al-Attar and then professor Mohamed Safwat Zahran, now Professor Ali Shams Aldeen.
    </string>
    <string name="benha_latitude">30.4706141</string>
    <string name="benha_Longitude">31.1814182</string>


    <string name="ain_shams">Ain Shams University</string>
    <string name="ain_shams_description">
        Ain Shams University is an institute of higher education located in Cairo,
        Egypt. Founded in 1950, the university provides education at the undergraduate, graduate and post-graduate levels.
        Ain Shams University was founded in July 1950, the third-oldest non-sectarian native public Egyptian university
        (ancient Islamic universities such as Al-Azhar and private institutions such as the American University in Cairo are older),
        under the name of Ibrahim Pasha's University. Its site used to be a former royal palace, called the Zafarana Palace. The two
        earlier universities of this kind are Cairo University (Fuad I university) and Alexandria University (Farouk I university).
        When it was first established
    </string>
    <string name="ain_shams_latitude">30.0938255</string>
    <string name="ain_shams_Longitude">31.2533663</string>


    <string name="red_sea">Red Sea</string>
    <string name="red_sea_description">
        The Red Sea (also the Erythraean Sea) is a seawater inlet of the Indian Ocean,
        lying between Africa and Asia. The connection to the ocean is in the south through the Bab el Mandeb
        strait and the Gulf of Aden. To the north lie the Sinai Peninsula, the Gulf of Aqaba, and the Gulf of Suez
        (leading to the Suez Canal). The Red Sea is a Global 200 ecoregion. The sea is underlain by the Red Sea Rift
        which is part of the Great Rift Valley.
    </string>
    <string name="red_sea_latitude">25.1520947</string>
    <string name="red_sea_Longitude">35.4219742</string>


    <string name="sharm_el_sheikh">Sharm El Sheikh</string>
    <string name="sharm_el_sheikh_description">
        Sharm El Sheikh is a city on the southern tip of the Sinai Peninsula, in South Sinai Governorate,
        Egypt, on the coastal strip along the Red Sea. Its population is approximately 73,000 as of 2015.
        Sharm El Sheikh is the administrative hub of Egypt\'s South Sinai Governorate, which includes the smaller
        coastal towns of Dahab and Nuweiba as well as the mountainous interior, St. Catherine and Mount Sinai.
        Although this city and holiday resort was a significant centre for tourism in Egypt, since the Metro Jet disaster
        it has lost popularity.
    </string>
    <string name="sharm_el_sheikh_latitude">27.9201492</string>
    <string name="sharm_el_sheikh_Longitude">34.2639883</string>

    <string name="alex">Alexandria</string>
    <string name="alex_description">
        Alexandria is the second largest city and a major economic centre in Egypt,
        extending about 32 km (20 mi) along the coast of the Mediterranean Sea in the north central part of the country.
        Its low elevation on the Nile delta makes it highly vulnerable to rising sea levels. Alexandria is an important
        industrial center because of its natural gas and oil pipelines from Suez. Alexandria is also a popular tourist destination.
    </string>
    <string name="alex_latitude">31.2240349</string>
    <string name="alex_Longitude">29.8147987</string>

</resources>
